Hannah Gardner Hattersley

Full Stack Software Developer

Austin, TX

hannahgardner96@gmail.com

(520) 609 – 1538

https://github.com/hannahgardner96

www.linkedin.com/in/hannah-mulligan-gardner

As a React and JavaScript developer with a background in education and the nonprofit sector, I am an experienced on-my-feet thinker who values data-informed, collaborative decisions and thoughtful communication. Rather than discourage me, bugs in code excite and motivate me to find an alternative creative solution. I am passionate about continuing my journey in technology, tackling complex challenges and building community as I go.

Skills

- Languages & Frameworks: TypeScript, React, JavaScript, Node, Express, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Skeleton, d3
- Management & Deployment: Git, GitHub, Command Line
- Databases: MongoDB
- Methodologies: Functional Programming, Object Oriented Programming, MVC Pattern, Responsive Design, Authentication, WireFraming

Education

University of Arizona, *Tucson, Arizona*August 2018
BA, Psychology
Minor, Latin American Studies

Software Experience

<u>Software Engineering Immersive Student</u>—*Remote* General Assembly, full time, 4/2021-7/2021

- 12-week, 500+ hour training program focused in Git/Github, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node, MongoDB, SQL, and Python.
- Developed an arcade web page that housed four fully functioning games
- Created a wellness tracker that took user data, created graphs to display trends, and allowed them to upload wellness resources to an index

Relevant Experience

Registered Behavior Technician—Austin, TX Cultivate BHE, full time, 6/2020-4/2021

- Implemented behavior plan for clients ages 2-6 on the autism spectrum, providing one-on-one therapy sessions.
- Ran behavioral intervention trials, recorded and tracked data, and used data real-time to inform decisions.

Amigos de las Americas

Cohort Director—Remote, 6/2020-8/2020

- Managed 3 college-aged mentors who supported 12 total high school volunteers in creating a community service project.
- Creatively implemented fully online curriculum, monitored project progress, balanced timezones, and provided feedback to both mentors and volunteers.

Associate Training Director—Houston, TX, 8/2019-5/2020

 Created and implemented training curriculum for over 50 high school students preparing to volunteer in various Latin American countries for 4-8 weeks, covering cultural sensitivity, sustainable development, and community engagement.

Supervisor—Matagalpa, Nicaragua, 5/2017-8/2017

• Supervised community-based initiative projects of 8 high school participants in 3 low-income, rural communities, providing emotional support, facilitating conflict resolution, and responding to health and safety needs.

<u>Teacher</u>—Houston, TX

Teach For America/Americorps & Klein Intermediate, full-time, 8/2018-5/2020

- Math teacher for regular, advanced, and sheltered (ESL, new arrivals) math classes.
- Team lead: Facilitated planning and modeling for all 6th grade math teachers.
- Klein ISD English Learner (EL) Guiding Coalition: Analyzed data to identify most significant obstacles facing current ELs in district and created EL curriculum guidelines for district based on findings.
- Founded Mental Health Awareness Club and sponsored National Junior Honor Society.
- Completed 20 hours of professional development each school year and 200 additional hours of training in pedagogy and systemic educational inequities through Teach For America/Americorps.